# Samantha Ponce

Brentwood, NY 11717 | 631-740-5034 | Samanthaponce5@gmail.com

Github: Samanthaponce5 | Blog: https://medium.com/@samanthaponce5 | Linkedin

#### SUMMARY

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming with a background in Dental Assisting which has provided me with strong skills in problem-solving, decision-making, organization, listening, and working under pressure. Can quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both teams and self-directed settings.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Skills include Ruby, Rails, Javascript, ReactJs, CSS, HTML

# **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Jack's Journey - Frontend | Backend | Demo

An interactive educational site where users learn more about plastic pollution and the effects it has on the ocean.

- Built by using a ReactJS library, and a Rails-API backend using Postgres database.
- Implemented vanilla CSS for design

# Picology - Frontend | Backend | Demo

Picology is an e-commerce site where users can navigate through a gallery ranging from nature, aerial, and city photography and can choose to buy any of the photography listed and checkout to have it mailed to their homes.

- Developed using a ReactJS library and a Rails-API backend using Postgres database.
- Applied vanilla CSS for design

### Omega Sound - Frontend | Backend | Demo

Omega Sound is designed to let users search and listen to any songs they would like.

- Created by using Vanilla Javascript and Rails-API backend
- Employed the Spotify API for music
- Design created with vanilla CSS

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Bellmore, NY Dental365 **Dental Assistant** 10/2019 - 03/2020

- Responsible for providing patient care, taking X-Rays, dental procedure assisting, sterilization.
- Decreased setup time for dental procedure preparation by 50%.
- Trained other staff members in X-Ray and assisting skills.

**HRHCare** Amityville, NY 01/2018 - 09/2019 Dental Assistant

#### **Great Expression Dental Centers**

Bayshore, NY Dental Assistant 03/2017 - 10/2017

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School New York, NY Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, React and JavaScript program 02/2020 - 06/2020

### **Suffolk Community College**

Associates in Liberal Arts and Science 06/2019

Brentwood, NY 09/2017 -